Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc. Records
Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc. Records
1930-1967
Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc.
31 linear ft.
Papers of the American publishing firm, including correspondence (1944-1966); general files, typescript manuscripts, production records, promotional material, books, and newspaper clippings.
148990
Biographical History
First established in 1943, Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc., is a trade independent book publisher in the United States, particularly strong in self-help and how-to titles.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc. Records is arranged in eight categories.
Correspondence is made up of letters both to and from Fell concerning business. General files is comprised of his business associates. Clippings and Advertising contain promotional material. Published material -- Other and Published material are composed of books, transcripts, and rough drafts of books. Memorabilia is composed of such items as address books, photographs, and a gag award. Business records and apparatus contains corporate stock ledgers and Fell's corporate seal.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is in chronological order. General files are in alphabetical order. The remaining material is in no particular order.
Related Material
has the records of several important American publishers, including Grove Press and Street and Smith. Please refer to the for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Fell, Frederick Victor, 1910-; Frederick Fell Publishers, Inc., -- Archives.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frederick Fell, 1967-1986.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1944-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Lelord Kordel (Box 1)
  - Writer's Digest (Box 1)
- General files
  - Miscellaneous, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Joey Adams (Box 2)
  - Advertising (Box 2)
  - John Alan Appleman (Box 2)
  - A.C. Appler (Box 2)
  - Applications for Employment (Box 2)
  - Evelyn Barkins (Box 2)
  - Barnes Management Library (Box 2)
  - Fred Benham (Box 2)
  - Millard Bennett, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Patricia Benton (Box 2)
  - Carl Breihan (Box 2)
  - Roger Brook (Box 2)
  - Albert Castel (Box 2)
  - Catalogs (Box 2)
  - Cha Cha Cha (Box 2)
  - Glen Clairmonte (Box 2)
  - Carlton Cole (Box 2)
  - Copyrights (Box 2)
  - Current Books (Box 2)
  - Eddie Davis (Box 3)
  - Dictation (Box 3)
  - Dikty and Bleiler (Box 3)
  - Editorial Services (Box 3)
  - George Feldman (Box 3)
  - Robert Franklyn (Box 3)
  - Vic Frederickr, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Walter Gibson (Box 3)
  - Leonard Green (Box 3)
  - Corrine Griffith (Box 3)
  - E. Wayne Hull (Box 3)
  - Jacket Material (Box 3)
  - William H. Jacobs (Box 3)
  - Ralph A. Jason (Box 3)
  - Harold Kahn (Box 3)
  - Ronald Kirkbride (Box 3)
  - Legal Material (Box 3)
  - Letterheads (Box 3)
  - Harry Lorayne (Box 3)
  - Mail Order Material (Box 3)
  - Edna Malcoskey (Box 3)
  - Conty Marlowe (Box 3)
  - Meadow Lane Co. (Box 3)
  - M.S. Michel (Box 3)
  - Harold Miller (Box 3)
  - Marsh Morrison (Box 3)
  - Names, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Bergen F. Newell (Box 3)
  - Notes (Box 3)
  - Dr. Miklos Nyiszli (Box 3)
  - Marjorie O'Shaughnessy (Box 3)
  - Paul Parker (Box 3)
  - Perfettes Manufacturing Company (Box 3)
  - Personal, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Dr. Frederick Price (Box 4)
  - Projects 52-53 (Box 4)
  - Prize Novel Award, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Receipts (Box 4)
  - Rejects, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Rock 'n' Roll (Box 4)
  - Lillian Roth, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Martin Rywell (Box 4)
  - Jerry Siegel (Box 4)
  - E.W. Smith (Box 4)
  - Social Security (Box 4)
  - Nan Shipley (Box 4)
  - Peter J. Steinchrow (Box 4)
  - F.B. Streeter (Box 4)
  - Turfmaster (Box 4)
  - University of Oregon (Box 4)
  - Irving Wallace (Box 4)
  - Western Americana (Box 4)
  - A.M. Winchester (Box 4)
  - Thyra Samter Wilson (Box 4)
  - John Worby (Box 4)
- Clippings
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, 6, 7)
- Advertising
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- Published material - other
  - Books
    - Eat, Think and Be Slender, 1954; 10 volumes (Box 9)
    - The Power of Inspired Salesmanship, 1960; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - How to Use Tact and Skill in Handling People, 1960; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - Jeg Genauer Mine Tarer, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Wollen Sie Länger Leben, Herr Direktor?, 1962; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - Tamiko, 1959; 1964; 2 volumes each, total 4 volumes (Box 9)
    - Alaskadokturn (Box 9)
    - How to Live to be 100, 1963; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - Auschwitz, 1960; 3 volumes (Box 9)
    - Calendar Model, 1958 (Box 9)
    - The Devil's Agent, 1959; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - Astounding Science Fiction, 1957 (Box 10)
    - I Romanzi di Urania, 1953; 7 volumes (Box 10)
    - How to Make Psychology Work for You, 1957; 3 volumes (Box 10)
    - A Man Divided, 1950 (Box 10)
    - Les Rois des Etoiles, undated (Box 10)
    - I Morgen Kan Jeg Grate, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Possess Me Not, 1948 (Box 10)
    - The Sins of Philip Fleming, 1959; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Memory of Love, 1943 (Box 10)
    - Como Adquirir una Super Memoria, 1959 (Box 10)
    - Jaggrater I Morgon, 1954 (Box 10)
    - What Today's Woman Should Know About Marriage, 1948 (Box 10)
    - Grammar Self-Taught, 1963; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Broken Melody, 1942 (Box 10)
    - As He Saw It, 1946 (Box 10)
    - Look To The Sun, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Painless Rectal Surgery, 1951 (Box 10)
    - The Yogurt Cookbook, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Die Malerei Des Barock, 1940 (Oversize 5)
  - Catalogs and Magazines
    - Miscellaneous, 16 volumes (Box 10)
- Published material
  - Books
    - Still the Heart Sings, 1950; 9 volumes (Box 11)
    - A Letter to the Man Who Killed My Dog, 1956; 5 volumes (Box 11)
    - Everyman's History of the Jews, 1948; 5 volumes (Box 11)
    - Off Limits, 1957; 3 volumes (Box 11)
    - All Dogs Go To Heaven, 1943; 5 volumes (Box 11)
    - Heads You Lose, 1950; 24 volumes (Box 12)
    - Beyond My Worth, 1958; 4 volumes (Box 12)
    - The One Eyed Poacher and the Maine Woods, 1955 (Box 12)
    - Marriage, Morals and War, 1943; 11 volumes (Box 13)
    - Mark It With a Stone, 1949; 9 volumes (Box 13)
    - Georgie May, 1928; 3 volumes (Box 13)
    - Inside Tin Pan Alley, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Virtuous Girl, 1949 (Box 13)
    - How to Be Sexcessful, 1958 (Box 13)
    - City At World's End, 1952; 6 volumes (Box 13)
    - Behind These Walls, 1957; 4 volumes (Box 13)
    - For Doctors Only, 1948; 2 volumes (Box 13)
    - Secrets of a Professional Coin Dealer, 1966 (Box 13)
    - I Vostri Piedi, 1956; 4 volumes (Box 14)
    - Your Feet Are Killing You, 1953; 3 volumes (Box 14)
    - The Bedside Bonanza, 1944; 6 volumes (Box 14)
    - The Star Kings, 1949; 3 volumes (Box 14)
    - Stjernefyrstens Sonn, 1951 (Box 14)
    - Out of My Darkness, 1957; 3 volumes (Box 14)
    - Jack the Ripper, 1960; 2 volumes (Box 14)
    - Four-Sided Triangle, 1951; 4 volumes (Box 14)
    - Planets for Sale, 1954; 3 volumes (Box 14)
    - A Treasury of Doctor's Stories, 1946 (Box 14)
    - Father Meany, 1944 (Box 14)
    - The 14-Karat Trailer, 1955 (Box 14)
    - Love Me Sailor, 1950; 7 volumes (Box 15)
    - Bridges to the Unknown, 1956; 3 volumes (Box 15)
    - How to Lose Weight The Doctor's Way, 1959 (Box 15)
    - The Freeze and Please Home Freezer Cookbook, 1963; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - Jest What the Doctor Ordered, 1949; 3 volumes (Box 15)
    - The Murder of Me, 1961; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - Psychiatry for the Millions, 4 volumes (Box 15)
    - Bed Manners and Better Bed Manners, 1941 (Box 15)
    - Four Children for the Doctor, 1955; 3 volumes (Box 15)
    - President Eisenhower's Cartoon Book, 1956; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - Are These Our Doctors?, 1952; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - Laugh, You Sinners, 1955; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - The "GUV", 1947; 9 volumes (Box 16)
    - Health The Easy Way (Box 16)
    - Why Seapower Will Win the War, 1944; 7 volumes (Box 16)
    - Gentlemen for Rent, 1955; 5 volumes (Box 16)
    - The Best Science Fiction Stories
      - 1949, 6 volumes (Box 16)
      - 1950, 2 volumes (Box 17)
      - 1951 (missing as of 6/4/08), 2 volumes (Box 17)
      - 1952, 2 volumes (Box 17)
      - 1953(missing as of 6/4/08), 2 volumes (Box 17)
      - 1954, 3 volumes (Box 17)
      - 1955, 2 volumes (Box 17)
    - Science Fiction Omnibus, 1949; 2 volumes (Box 17)
    - Year's Best Science Fiction Novels, 1952; 1953,; 1955 (Box 17)
    - Fellow Citizens, 1950; 4 volumes (Box 17)
    - Developing Bosom Beauty, 1959 (Box 17)
    - I'll Cry Tomorrow, 1955; 2 volumes (Box 17)
    - Winds Blow Gently, 1945; 2 volumes (Box 17)
    - Fatu's Experiences, 1953; 8 volumes (Box 18)
    - The Trial of Dr. DeKaplany, 1965; 2 volumes (Box 18)
    - El Jukio del Dr. DeKaplany, 1967; 3 volumes (Box 18)
    - The Wild West Joke Book, 1956; 2 volumes (Box 18)
    - Jacob and the Angel, 1961 (Box 18)
    - Fell's United States Coin Book, 1955; 2 volumes (Box 18)
    - My Father-My Son, 1958 (Box 18)
    - Day Unto Day, 1943 (Box 18)
    - The Scarlet Lily, 1959 (Box 18)
    - In The Footsteps of Sherlock Holmes, 1960 (Box 18)
    - The Family Problems Handbook, 1952 (Box 18)
    - Bist Du Normal, 1951 (Box 18)
    - A Friend is for Always, 1963 (Box 18)
    - Hospital Happy, 1959 (Box 18)
    - Taxation With Representation or Your Money Went That-A-Way, 1962 (Box 18)
    - Know Your Hay Fever, 1943 (Box 18)
    - The Curtain Never Falls, 1949 (Box 18)
    - For Maine Only, 1959 (Box 18)
    - My Friend Ike, 1956 (Box 18)
    - Naked on Roller Skates, 1930 (Box 18)
    - Fell's Guide to the Secrets of Self Hypnosis, 1964 (Box 18)
  - Typescripts
    - Joy for Daily Living (Box 19)
    - I'm Lucky at Cards (Box 19)
    - This You Won't Believe (Box 19)
    - The Diabetic Cookbook (Box 19)
    - Face Language (Box 19)
    - Al Kelly s Double Life (Box 19)
    - More Life More Years (Box 19)
    - How to Win Sweepstakes Prizes (Box 19)
    - Decisions and the Furies (Box 19)
    - The Condominium Buyer's Guide (Box 19)
    - Writing for Juveniles (Box 19)
    - The Cheskin System for Business Success (Box 19)
    - How to Use the Power of Enthusiasm (Box 19)
    - Fell's Guide to Winning Backgammon (Box 19)
    - Firefly Moments (Box 19)
    - The Famous and the Infamous (Box 19)
    - I Dive for Treasure (Box 20)
    - Scientific Man (Box 20)
    - Our Murdered Presidents (Box 20)
    - How to Develop Your ESP Power (Box 20)
    - Does Your Mother Know (Box 20)
    - Common Stock for the Uncommon Man (Box 20)
    - How to Finance a Growing Business (Box 20)
    - How to Improve Your Speaking Voice (Box 20)
    - Mail Order Business (Box 20)
    - Momma and Me Plus Three (Box 20)
    - Fell's Guide to Hand Puppets (Box 20)
    - Appointment With Success (Box 20)
    - It Happened On Rush Street (Box 20)
    - El Vendedor Mas Grande (Box 20)
    - By Way of Introduction (Box 20)
    - Investing in Natural Resources (Box 21)
    - How to Develop Power and Confidence in Selling Real Estate (Box 21)
    - Your Success Through Psycho-Cybernetics (Box 21)
    - Cooking With Health Foods (Box 21)
    - I Can Heal Myself and I Will (Box 21)
    - The Greatest Miracle in the World How to Manage Yourself (Box 21)
    - How to Earn $25,000 a Year or More Typing at Home (Box 21)
    - The Encyclopedia of Little Known, Highly Profitable Business Opportunities (Box 21)
    - The New Encyclopedia of Little Known Highly Profitable Business Opportunities (Box 21)
    - How to Profit from the Coming Land Boom in the Caribbean Islands and Latin America (Box 21)
    - Born in April, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Building Sales Confidence (Box 22)
    - I'll Cry Tomorrow (Box 22)
    - The Trial of Dr. DeKaplany (Box 22)
    - The Golden Children (Box 22)
    - It's Never Too Late, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - The Escapades of Frank and Jesse James (Box 22)
    - The Incompleat Man, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - The Boston Police Diet and Maintenance Program, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - The Complete Guide to Acupuncture, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Fell's Complete Guide to Buried Treasure, Land and Sea, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - The Schoolteachers (Box 23)
    - Techniques for Discovering Hidden Value Stocks, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - A Philosophy of Self Management, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Winds Blow Gently (Box 23)
    - Arizona (Box 23)
    - Uncle Sam as Your Information Finder (Box 24)
    - From Gags to Riches (Box 24)
    - Fell's Official Stamp Guide, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Crackers in Bed (Box 24)
    - Great Science Fiction Stories About Mars (Box 24)
    - A Grandparent's Garden of Verses (Box 24)
    - How to Double Your Child's Power to Read (Box 24)
    - Cooking With Yogurt (Box 24)
    - The Greatest Secret in the World (Box 24)
    - The Drug Plague (Box 24)
    - Kick the Habit (Box 24)
    - Untitled (John A. O'Brien) (Box 24)
    - Short Cuts Math, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Short stories
    - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Galleys
    - How to Develop Power and Confidence in Selling Real Estate (Box 25)
    - From Gags to Riches (Box 25)
    - By Way of Introduction (Box 25)
    - The Schoolteachers (Box 25)
    - I Can Heal Myself and I Will (Box 25)
    - A Philosophy of Self Management (Box 25)
    - How to Use the Power of Enthusiasm (Box 25)
    - Secrets of Self Hypnosis (Box 26)
    - Writing for Juveniles (Box 26)
    - Fell's Guide to Buried Treasure, Land and Sea (Box 26)
    - Great Science Fiction Stories About Mars (Box 26)
    - Whistle on the Wind (Box 26)
    - Of the Heart's Own Telling (Box 26)
    - Mail Order (Box 26)
    - Untitled (Robert N. Newcomb) (Box 26)
    - Never too Late to Be Young (Box 26)
    - Untitled (?) (Box 26)
  - Cartoons
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, oversize (Oversize 4)
  - Photographs
    - Joe Di Maggio (Box 26)
    - Lillian Roth (Box 26)
    - Religious (Box 26)
    - Porcelain Art (Box 26)
    - The Old West (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Illustration Plates, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Lay Outs
    - Fatu's Experiences (Box 27)
    - F.D.R. Picture Story (Box 27)
    - Hospital Happy (Box 27)
    - Developing the Bosom (Box 27)
    - Food Values (Box 27)
    - Can You (Box 27)
    - President Eisenhower's Cartoon Book (Box 27)
    - Unknown title (Benge Stock Book) (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 2)
    - Salty The Seahorse (Oversize 3)
    - Can You (Oversize 3)
    - Fellow Citizens (Oversize 3)
    - Super Memory Power (Oversize 4)
    - LBJ's Texas Laughs (Oversize 4)
    - War and Peace (Oversize 4)
- Memorabilia
  - Photographs (Box 27)
  - Award (Box 27)
  - Phonograph record (Box 27)
  - Address books, 13 volumes (Box 27)
  - Scrapbooks, 5 volumes (Oversize 1)
- Business records and apparatus
  - Stock certificates ledger (Box 27)
  - Stock and transfer ledger (Box 27)
  - Minutes book (Box 27)
  - Corporate seal (Box 27)
  - Printer plates, 6 plates (Box 28)